YUNZHE WANG

784 Columbus Ave, New York, NY

(213) - 421 - 9274 | yw3737@columbia.edu | Home Page: yunzhew.com

OBJECTIVE

With an interdisciplinary passion for Artificial Intelligence and Cognitive Science, I seek to answer: "What is intelligence and how should we recreate it?" I envision General AI emerging in the next 5-10 years, and I want its primary purpose to be assisting and augmenting human capabilities. Keywords below best encapsulates my interests:

Self-supervised Learning, Few-Shot Learning, Multi-Modal Learning, Cognitive Modeling, Intelligent Agent, Multi-Agent System Human-AI Interaction and Collaboration, Augmented Intelligence, Assistive Technologies, AI Safety and Alignment, Fairness

EDUCATION

Columbia University (GPA: 3.96/4.00)

M.S. Computer Science, Machine Learning Track

Aug 2021 - May 2023

New York, NY

University of Southern California (GPA: 3.84/4.00)

B.S. Computational Neuroscience

B.A. Applied Mathematics Minor Computer Science

Los Angeles, CA Aug 2017 - May 2021

Relevant Coursework: Machine Learning, Unsupervised Learning, Natural Language Processing, Reinforcement Learning, Applied Computer Vision, Artificial Intelligence, Robotics, Cognitive Neuroscience, Sensation and Perception, Neurobiology, Brain Architecture, Cellular and Molecular Neuroscience, Statistics, Probability Theory, Numerical Methods, Calculus, Optimization, Computer Networks, Social Networks, Databases, Data Structure, Algorithm Analysis, Advanced Algorithms

EXPERIENCE

Bubble Group, Inc. - A leader in the no-code tech domain

Software Engineer II (Artificial Intelligence)

New York, NY Iul 2023 - Present

- Conducted Generative AI research and development in text-to-web-application generation.
- Initiated and led the LLM-Agent Approach, enabling generating stylistic and responsive websites directly from natural language. Emphasized scalability, cost-efficiency, and time.
- Formulated a vision-based Reward Model, conducted LLM-tuning and dataset EDA, and streamlined code integration.
- Gained proficiency in processing data modalities including Natural Language Text, Code, and Images.

Creative Machines Lab at Columbia University

Student Researcher

New York, NY Sep 2021 - May 2023

• Machine Learning and Robotics research with Prof. Hod Lipson

Project: Conversational Face Robot

- Collaborated on creating a conversational face robot with human-like lip-sync and co-expressive facial dynamics.
- Led the Machine Learning Aspects:
 - o Designed a speech-driven talking face generation model, enhancing the robot with verbal interaction capabilities.
 - Utilized self-supervised learning, achieving model robustness for varied speakers and languages with limited data.
 - Utilized GAN, LSTM, and Multi-Modal Transformer architectures, modalities in speech, videos, and 3D landmarks.

Project: Quadruped Robot Morphology Transfer Learning

- Developed a 12-DOF quadruped robot capable of self-morphology identification and realtime trajectory optimization.
- Led the Machine Learning Aspects:
 - o Developed a classifier capable of identifying 12-DOF robot morphologies from motion dynamics, enabled trajectory optimization for robot with unseen morphologies.
 - o Utilized Transfer Learning and Multi-Task Learning; Data modalities in time-series (IMU) and point cloud.

Cognitive Architecture Lab at USC Institute for Creative Technologies

Los Angeles, CA

Student Researcher

Feb 2020 - Aug 2021

- Reinforcement Learning and Operational Research with Prof. Paul Rosenbloom and Dr. Volkan Ustun.
- Software development for the Graphical Model aspects of the (Py)Sigma Cognitive Architecture.

Project: DARPA Artificial Social Intelligence for Successful Teams (ASIST)

- Developed a decision-making framework for human search-and-rescue teams, resulting in real-time routing suggestions that surpassed the performance of conventional RL and Linear Programming methods.
- Leveraged Graph Transformer, Reinforcement learning, and Unsupervised Learning; Data modalities in Graph.

Institute of Computing Technology, Chinese Academy of Science

Beijing, China May 2019 - Aug 2019

Research Internship

- Natural Language Processing Research mentored by Prof. Cungen Cao, focused on Knowledge Extraction.
- Led and developed an expert system to optimize Chinese Part-of-Speech tagging models, leveraging automated datamined rules and advanced pattern matching algorithms.

PUBLICATIONS

Efficient Transfer Learning Across Robot Morphologies

Y. Hu, Y. Wang, R. Liu, Z. Shen, H. Lipson.

Submitted to International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA 2024)

Lip Synchronization for Animatronic Robot Face

2021 - 2023

2022 - 2023

Y. Hu, Yu. Wang, B. Chen, Yi. Wang, J. Lin, H. Lipson.

In Submission to Science Robotics

Human-Robot Facial Co-expression

2021 - 2023

Y. Hu, B. Chen, J. Lin, Yu. Wang, Yi. Wang, H. Lipson.

Science Robotics (In Revision)

Route Optimization in Service of a Search and Rescue Artificial Social Intelligence Agent

2020 - 2021

Y. Wang, N. Gurney, J. Zhou, D. Pynadath, V. Ustun.

Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence 2021 Fall Symposium Series (AAAI FSS 2021)

TEACHING

Applied C	omnuter	Vision	(Teaching	(Assistant)
Applieu C	unputer	V 121011	(i eaciiiii)	, Assistant j

Spring 2023

Introduction to Natural Language Processing (Teaching Assistant)

Fall 2022

Introduction to Natural Language Processing (Teaching Assistant)

Summer 2022

AWARDS

USC Graduate with Distinction (Magna Cum Laude)

Academic Achievement Award, University of Southern California

Dean's List, all semesters, University of Southern California

American Mathematical Contest 12 (top 5%), Mathematical Association of America

PROJECTS

M. D. MAZ., ALTO.	1:1 / 1: 1	2022
Medium Writer on AI Topics	bit.ly/medium-yunzhe	2023
Interactive Visualization of 1.7M Arxiv Papers	bit.ly/arxiv-embed-viz	2023
Audio-Visual Speaker Diarization	bit.ly/syncnet-spk	2023
Unsupervised Neural Machine Translation	bit.ly/unmt-survey	2022
Autonomous Car-Racing Game Agent in Unity	bit.ly/auto-drive-agent	2021

SKILLS

Programming and Development: Python, C++, SQL, JavaScript/TypeScript, Git, LaTeX, Web Development, Web Scraping

AI and Machine Learning: PyTorch, scikit-learn, Tensor Programming, Data Visualization, Deep Learning, Reinforcement Learning, Unsupervised Learning, Sequence Modeling, Prompt Engineering, Large Language Model

Others: Bilingual in English and Chinese, Photography, Drawing, Culinary